<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Office Hours on CSRGO Blog</title><link>https://blog.csrgo.com/tags/office-hours/</link><description>Recent content in Office Hours on CSRGO Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 04:33:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.csrgo.com/tags/office-hours/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>India’s Right to Disconnect Bill 2025 — After-Work Calls, New Rules, and How It Impacts You</title><link>https://blog.csrgo.com/posts/indias-right-to-disconnect-bill-2025--after-work-calls-new-rules-and-how-it-impacts-you/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 04:33:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.csrgo.com/posts/indias-right-to-disconnect-bill-2025--after-work-calls-new-rules-and-how-it-impacts-you/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-what-is-the-right-to-disconnect-bill-2025"&gt;🔎 What Is the Right to Disconnect Bill 2025?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new legislative proposal called the &lt;strong&gt;Right to Disconnect Bill 2025&lt;/strong&gt; has been introduced to give every employee the legal right to &lt;strong&gt;disconnect from work after official hours&lt;/strong&gt;. That means no mandatory replies to calls, emails, messages or video-calls once office time ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="-key-provisions"&gt;✅ Key Provisions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employees are &lt;strong&gt;not obliged&lt;/strong&gt; to respond to work-related communication after work hours or on holidays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be &lt;strong&gt;no disciplinary action&lt;/strong&gt; or negative consequences if an employee chooses not to respond after hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If extra work beyond office hours is required and agreed upon, it must count as &lt;strong&gt;overtime&lt;/strong&gt; with appropriate compensation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workplaces must clearly define emergency or on-call requirements, instead of assuming “always-on” availability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In short:&lt;/strong&gt; the bill aims to &lt;strong&gt;restore a clear boundary between “work time” and “personal time”&lt;/strong&gt; — giving employees a legal shield against the pressure of being reachable 24×7.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>